Guide to the International Ladies Garment Workers Union Records, 1924-1953 and undated RL.11305
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
International Ladies Garment Workers Union records
1924-1953 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
International Ladies' Garment Workers Union
RL.11305
0.5 Linear Feet
Assorted manuals and publications produced by the International Ladies Garment Workers Union and its various local unions.
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU) was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States, one of the first U.S. unions to have a primarily female membership, and a key player in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union, generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG," merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The International Ladies Garment Workers Union Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer from Perkins Library in 2012.
Collection Overview
Collective agreements, union literature, and publications from the ILGWU Educational Department, as well as assorted publications from various local unions, including the Dressmakers, Beltmakers, Shirtmakers, Office and Distribution Employees, and others. Materials address issues of workers' rights, the benefits of unionization, communism (including anti-communist efforts within the union), governance of the unions, and union history.
Labor unions; Communism -- United States; International Ladies' Garment Workers Union
- Constitutions, other literature, 1924-1950 (Box 1)
- Local 10 (Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters), undated (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Handbook
- Local 22 (Dressmakers), 1940s; 2 folders (Box 1)
  Union pamphlets, booklets; political literature, including American Labor Party
- Local 23 (Shirtmakers), 1952 (Box 1)
  Booklets
- Local 40 (Beltmakers), 1935 (Box 1)
  Union booklet
- Local 99 (Office and Distribution Employees), undated (Box 1)
- Local 105 (Infants and Children's Clothing), 1953 and undated (Box 1)
  Union booklets
- "The Position of the I.L.G.W.U. in Relation to CIO and AFL 1934-1938" (Box 1)
  Draft
- "Communist Plague in our Unions", undated (Box 1)
- Educational Department publications, music, 1934-1950 (Box 1)
  Handbooks, union benefit flyers, etc.
- Northeast Department publication, undated (Box 1)
  "My Name is Mary Brown" musical
- Collective agreements with dress manufacturers, 1936 and undated (Box 1)
  Includes proofs and final copies.
- Conventions, including Golden Jubilee, 1950, 1953 (Box 1)
  Calendars, local reports, etc.
- Receipts and Disbursements of Funds, 1951-1953 (Box 1)
- Training Institute flyer, 1953 (Box 1)
  Recruitment flyer
- UAW-CIO Education Department publicatons, 1945-1948 (Box 1)